<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="051DDAD0-2705-41A9-A592-10C44D84EB5E">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20121130" date="2012-11-30 11:50:11 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Projects</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>First PCB layout!</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>March 1, 2012</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_First_PCB_layout%21_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="424px" height="306px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>As a mechanical engineer in Berkeley, learning how to print printed circuit boards (PCBs) was not part of the standard curriculum. However, through my research on &lt;a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&amp;arnumber=6094658&amp;contentType=Conference+Publications&amp;searchField%3DSearch_All%26queryText%3Devan+chang+siu"&gt;Tailbot&lt;/a&gt;, a robot that mimics Agama lizards tail-assisted self-righting abilities, with &lt;a href="http://me.berkeley.edu/~evancs/index.html"&gt;Evan Chang Siu&lt;/a&gt;, I got a chance to learn how to use &lt;a href="http://www.cadsoftusa.com/"&gt;EAGLE&lt;/a&gt;.&#xD;&#xD;In MSC lab, there is a board milling machine that mills out PCBs from copper plates. This allowed me to design circuit boards and then print them in the machine to receive operable circuit boards without the expensive and long turnover time from traditional PCB printers.&#xD;&#xD;At first, I designed a breakout board for a simple SMD inverter (74LVC2G04). It was simple and all of the traces are on one side as well. This board simply alternates turning on the LEDs, depending on what signals are fed into the chip.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Drawing inspiration from &lt;a href="http://www.sparkfun.com/tutorials/138"&gt;Sparkfun&#x2019;s pogo beds&lt;/a&gt;, I then laid out a test probe board suitable for the Finch Chip, which was a wireless IMU with a tiny footprint developed by another graduate student in CiBER. Since the Finch Chip sacrificed headers for a small footprint, this test probe board breaks out all of the pins for repeatable and easy programming. As seen below, the Finch Chip would sit in the middle and the headers in the periphery would allow for programming and probing.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Finally, I began work on the second iteration of Tailbot&#x2019;s control board. In order to free up several pins on the Arduino, I added an inverter to reduce the logic lines required to control the motor. In addition, I replaced the slow XBee and installed a Nordic transceiver (nRF24L01+) for the control board&#x2019;s wireless communications. The board schematic shown below features the inverter, which is placed on the bottom layer beneath the words &#x201C;Tailbot v2&#x201D; while the Nordic transceiver was placed towards the lower left of the board.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Once it is printed and populated, it would look like this. Ain&#x2019;t she a beauty?</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
