<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="051DDAD0-2705-41A9-A592-10C44D84EB5E">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20130514" date="2013-05-14 19:51:56 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Projects</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Calopoly</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>May 10, 2013</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="10_Calopoly_Game_files/shapeimage_1.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="420px" height="200px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>As a final group project for E177, I, along with Henry Pham, Stephanie Su, and Melissa Wah participated in an endeavor to recreate the classic Monopoly game with a UC Berkeley twist. The project emphasized the usage of MATLAB&#x2019;s in built graphical user interface functions. Living up to that promise, we spent many hours worth of effort into making the game visually appealing. If you want to take a look at what we have made, you can download it &lt;a href="http://db.tt/bffQn9wa"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Simply add the folder to your MATLAB path and type CalopolyGame in the command window to start playing!&#xD;&#xD;Our Calopoly game is fully functional and retains much of Monopoly&#x2019;s original rules. One exception is that there is only one Get Out of Jail, or Get Out of Academic Probation, card. (We were lazy and didn&#x2019;t want to make a different one) &#xD;&#xD;One cool feature in our Calopoly game is that every player has a bunch of boxes that represents all of the game&#x2019;s title deeds. Once you own that property, the box fills in. If it is mortgaged, it turns a sickly brown to represent that. At any time, you can click on the box to have a title deed show up.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Our game also has a dice roll animation to show you what you rolled.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Moreover, when an unbought property is not bought by a visiting player, an auction begins that allows all remaining players to bid for the property.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;All actions a player can take is set out in two rows of buttons towards the end of the GUI&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Another cool feature is that the trade screen is very interactive; players make selections by selecting on title deed cards.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;One distinctive feature for our Calopoly game is that we custom made most of our graphics: the game board, the title deeds, and even the pictures we took of the actual places referenced in our Calopoly game. To view them, you can click on a particular tile in the game board to have it display.&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;As we neared the conclusion of our project, my group and I realized the extent of the foundation that must be set for a standard Monopoly game. We wrote almost over 3000 lines of code ( I did a lot less :P ) and took almost a month to bring the final product we have today. In retrospect, we should have picked a project that did not have as extensive of a backend as Monopoly because ultimately, the backend isn&#x2019;t regarded as highly as the project presentation, which would place heavy emphasis on the functionalities and presentation. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;From left to right, Stephanie Su, Henry Pham, Melissa Wah, and me&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;Regardless, we had a fun time making our Calopoly game and learned, to our surprise, how much MATLAB can do.&#xD;&#xD;Download link: &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://db.tt/bffQn9wa"&gt;CalopolyGame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
