<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects</title>
    <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects</link>
    <description>This page lists several projects I have participated or am undertaking during my time at Berkeley. Some of these projects were course projects while others were research assignments. Some projects I have spent entire semesters toiling over while others, I have spent as little as 13 days. True story.</description>
    <item>
      <title>Calopoly</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2013/5/10_Calopoly_Game.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">25e16945-a4cb-42d7-9b17-1c1ddb38888f</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 17:02:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>As a final group project for E177, I, along with Henry Pham, Stephanie Su, and Melissa Wah participated in an endeavor to recreate the classic Monopoly game with a UC Berkeley twist. The project emphasized the usage of MATLAB&#x2019;s in built graphical user interface functions. Living up to that promise, we spent many hours worth of effort into making the game visually appealing. If you want to take a look at what we have made, you can download it &lt;a href="http://db.tt/bffQn9wa"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Simply add the folder to your MATLAB path and type CalopolyGame in the command window to start playing!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our Calopoly game is fully functional and retains much of Monopoly&#x2019;s original rules. One exception is that there is only one Get Out of Jail, or Get Out of Academic Probation, card. (We were lazy and didn&#x2019;t want to make a different one) &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One cool feature in our Calopoly game is that every player has a bunch of boxes that represents all of the game&#x2019;s title deeds. Once you own that property, the box fills in. If it is mortgaged, it turns a sickly brown to represent that. At any time, you can click on the box to have a title deed show up.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our game also has a dice roll animation to show you what you rolled.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Moreover, when an unbought property is not bought by a visiting player, an auction begins that allows all remaining players to bid for the property.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;All actions a player can take is set out in two rows of buttons towards the end of the GUI&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Another cool feature is that the trade screen is very interactive; players make selections by selecting on title deed cards.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;One distinctive feature for our Calopoly game is that we custom made most of our graphics: the game board, the title deeds, and even the pictures we took of the actual places referenced in our Calopoly game. To view them, you can click on a particular tile in the game board to have it display.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As we neared the conclusion of our project, my group and I realized the extent of the foundation that must be set for a standard Monopoly game. We wrote almost over 3000 lines of code ( I did a lot less :P ) and took almost a month to bring the final product we have today. In retrospect, we should have picked a project that did not have as extensive of a backend as Monopoly because ultimately, the backend isn&#x2019;t regarded as highly as the project presentation, which would place heavy emphasis on the functionalities and presentation. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;From left to right, Stephanie Su, Henry Pham, Melissa Wah, and me&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Regardless, we had a fun time making our Calopoly game and learned, to our surprise, how much MATLAB can do.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Download link: &lt;a href="http://db.tt/bffQn9wa"&gt;CalopolyGame&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object006.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2013/5/10_Calopoly_Game.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Autonomous Robotic Network</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2013/5/3_Mobile_Autonomous_Robotic_Network.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d2878cfd-4ab2-4721-bdf0-1fa05f8b8fa1</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 3 May 2013 23:16:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>This project is officially done! I am very happy to have had a chance to work with my awesome team members to make this project a success!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As part of the class requirement, we made a website that highlighted milestones in our project. For more in depth information and visual appeal, check out our website at &lt;a href="http://me.berkeley.edu/~dwai/MAN"&gt;this url&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Our team members (clockwise from me): Ben Yee, Jared Porter, Robert Luan, and Stephen Chen&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lesson learned: It&#x2019;s good to stay on the ground. Building swarm robots can get really expensive. Our total cost neared $1000 for 5 robots. Also, building a project with an interactive, audience engaging, demonstration will help secure votes for the $500 grand prize at Demo Day.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object022.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2013/5/3_Mobile_Autonomous_Robotic_Network.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Losi Tailbot</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/6/9_Robot_with_Inertial_Assisted_Control_by_an_Active_Tail_Inspired_by_Lizards.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">55027430-16e4-4d11-ad17-2877f1de2305</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 9 Jun 2012 23:43:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>Status update:&lt;br/&gt;Continuing my work with the Mechanical Systems Control Lab, I worked over the summer in &lt;a href="http://ciber.berkeley.edu/"&gt;Center for Interdisciplinary Bio-Inspiration for Education and Research&lt;/a&gt; (CiBER) to create an upgraded version of the pre-existing &lt;a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?tp=&amp;arnumber=6094658"&gt;Tailbot&lt;/a&gt; with pitch control. In addition to sporting a weighted carbon fiber tail with a off the shelf &lt;a href="http://www.losi.com/"&gt;Losi&lt;/a&gt; RC car as the chassis, the new Tailbot would have increased maneuverability compared to its predecessor. (i.e. turn left and right)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As of now, I have finished the mechanical assembly for Losi Tailbot, which means the tail and its associated actuators are mounted and, when powered, will cause the tail to go through its range of motion. The next steps involve supplementing my robot with electronics to control the tail. Can&#x2019;t wait to see this project finish!</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object000.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/6/9_Robot_with_Inertial_Assisted_Control_by_an_Active_Tail_Inspired_by_Lizards.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Externally Dispersed Interferometer</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/6/9_Externally_Dispersed_Interferometer.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">dd4f419a-8d19-4bb7-b927-c3b8650f2ebe</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 9 Jun 2012 23:43:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>Telescopes in observatories like the Lick Observatory are used to gaze deep into the night sky for new planets near stars. However, limitations such as Earth&#x2019;s atmosphere makes it difficult to procure data with high resolution. Traditionally, a larger observatory with a bigger telescope would be built to address this issue but due to existing constraints, this is impossible for the Lick Observatory. To combat this problem from another angle, the Externally Dispersed Interferometer (EDI) was developed as an add-on to Lick Observatory&#x2019;s spectrograph to improve its spectral resolution by up to ten times.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Over the summer of 2012, I had the opportunity to work as an engineering assistant at &lt;a href="https://www.ssl.berkeley.edu/"&gt;Space Science Labs&lt;/a&gt; to design and build a new EDI for the Lick Observatory. First, I constructed the optical layout in Solidworks, which provided constraints on where all the EDI&#x2019;s constituent pieces can go. Because the optics used in the EDI are incompatible with most off the shelf hardware, I also had to design novel holders for etalons as long as 3&#x201D; as well as mirrors with no mounting features. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fun with liquid nitrogen. Here, we are pouring liquid nitrogen into the dewar of the CCD camera before we use the spectrometer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Isometric view of the interferometer that I worked on this summer. The gray lines converge into the beam splitter (green) in the center and reemerges on the other side to the rotary stage and linear stage (pictured top) where a combination of mirrors and lens create different optical distances for light to travel through. This &#x201C;delayed&#x201D; light combines with the original light to create DeMoire patterns that can be deciphered to glean additional information about the star. </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object019.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/6/9_Externally_Dispersed_Interferometer.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relativistic and non-relativistic orbits</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/5/10_Relativistic_and_non-relativistic_orbits.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d7a9d9fc-a6b0-49ca-9387-804a3d4145af</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 23:29:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>ME275 is the first grad class I have taken at Cal and the third class I have taken with &lt;a href="http://www.me.berkeley.edu/~oreilly/"&gt;Professor O&#x2019;Reilly&lt;/a&gt;. ME275&#x2019;s course title is Advanced Dynamics and delves into Lagrangian and Hamiltonian equations of motion. The course culminates into an individual group project that further explores a concept previously learned in class.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After being exposed to the ideas of relativity in the class, Professor O&#x2019;Reilly suggested I compare the Mercury&#x2019;s orbit in the relativistic and non-relativistic case. For the uninitiated, non-relativistic is grounded in Newtonian gravity and that it is a force of attraction between two massive objects. The &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_relativity"&gt;relativistic case&lt;/a&gt; is rooted in that planetary orbits are a result of the geometry of space-time, warped by gravity.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After setting forth the Lagrangian equations of motion for the two body system and applying a coordinate transformation, I plotted the system&#x2019;s phase portrait using &lt;a href="http://math.rice.edu/~dfield/dfpp.html"&gt;pplane&lt;/a&gt; to analyze their orbits.&lt;br/&gt;For the non-relativistic case, the phase portrait is as shown:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The phase portrait for the relativistic case, near and far from the origin (left and right) is shown below:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As seen above, the non-relativistic orbits form closed loops, which is expected in order to produce the physical orbits (from circular to hyperbolic) we observed in the universe. However, the relativistic phase portraits tell us a slightly different message. In the far view, the phase portraits look similar in the sense that there are closed loops encircling a red dot, the equilibrium distance. However, for some initial conditions in the relativistic case, such as being close to the origin (0,0), the phase portrait goes haywire and demonstrates a behavior to converge on (1,0), as seen in the left top portrait. This strange behavior is actually a manifestation of a black hole, as predicted by Einstein&#x2019;s theories. For initial conditions that pass beyond the vertical line at x = 1, it would implicate that the object has slipped beyond the event horizon of the black hole and would be lost forever. How&#x2019;s that for cool?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Fortunately for us, relativistic effects (especially black holes) on orbits are only significant when the two bodies are extremely close to one another. Mercury is an example of a planet that is close enough to experience minor relativistic effects. Integrating the results of the aforementioned phase portraits, I reconstructed the Mercury&#x2019;s physical orbits for the non-relativistic and relativistic case.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For the non-relativistic orbits, depending on your initial conditions with origin at (0,0), I saw that circular orbit (blue) can transform into more eccentric orbits (cyan) until finally it becomes parabolic and hyperbolic orbits (green and magenta, respectively). We can observe this in Earth, which has an orbit with low eccentricity and for comets, which has orbits that are highly hyperbolic.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For the relativistic case, I observed that changing the initial conditions generated a response characterized above. Irresistibly pretty, Mercury&#x2019;s orbit precesses around the origin (0,0) as time goes on. In green, Mercury&#x2019;s orbit for one Mercury year is shown. Six Mercury years later, Mercury&#x2019;s orbit (magenta) will have precessed and be physically in a different place. This behavior was one of the supporting evidence for Einstein&#x2019;s theories because Newtonian gravity couldn&#x2019;t have explained this behavior that scientists and physicists observed. Now, I appreciate Einstein even more.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For a complete analysis of this work, which I have summarized above, you may download my &lt;a href="http://db.tt/TPKg72BX"&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt;. All figures were created in MATLAB.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object020.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/5/10_Relativistic_and_non-relativistic_orbits.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ball on a Plate</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/5/2_Ball_on_a_Plate.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7324e306-473c-4542-b7a5-d6c0825bfe90</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 2 May 2012 17:20:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>ME135&#x2019;s course title is &#x201C;Design of Microprocessor-Based Mechanical Systems&#x201D; and it is as simple as that. The entire class focuses on building a single project with your group that demonstrates real time programming and sensor feedback. Robert Luan, Stephen Chen and I spent a hefty amount of time over dinner deciding on what our project was going to be. This course was notorious for having many quadrotor projects and so we wanted to shy away from that. Having spent almost 5 hours in Robert&#x2019;s home, we finally decided that our project was going to be a rendition of the Ball on a Plate, a system that aims to control the position of a ball on a square plate through feedback control. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To actuate the plate, we used two TowerPro servos on two independent axes below the plate (below). Although we initially used a ping pong ball for our system, we ended up choosing smaller metal ball bearings. Our plate was a polycarbonate/black foam PVC sandwich and it sits underneath an overhanging Logitech C520 webcam.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The sensory feedback comes from the webcam (below), which is taking a series of snapshots that are sent via USB to LabVIEW running on my computer. Since we&#x2019;ve limited the webcam&#x2019;s region of interest to the black plate, our shiny metal ball was easily detected using LabVIEW&#x2019;s inbuilt blob tracking image processing technique. However, we eventually switched to centroid (an average of all bright pixels) for its speed of execution.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To fulfill the real-time criteria, our Ball on a Plate relies on a NI sbRIO9606 to execute real-time control strategies, which included LQR and PID. My role in the project focused primarily on setting up the LabVIEW architecture for our system as well as programming (dragging wires around) additional features, such as the imposing a user generated trajectory over a streaming feed of images.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After many long nights, we finally finished our project, albeit not quite up to our initial expectations. Regardless, I was very satisfied and am still amazed at what we were able to accomplish in 13 days. </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object004.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/5/2_Ball_on_a_Plate.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First PCB layout!</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/3/1_First_PCB_layout%21.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">fc37de13-c6fe-4b8d-a662-46d0c9f0f54e</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 1 Mar 2012 00:01:33 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>As a mechanical engineer in Berkeley, learning how to print printed circuit boards (PCBs) was not part of the standard curriculum. However, through my research on &lt;a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/articleDetails.jsp?tp=&amp;arnumber=6094658&amp;contentType=Conference+Publications&amp;searchField%3DSearch_All%26queryText%3Devan+chang+siu"&gt;Tailbot&lt;/a&gt;, a robot that mimics Agama lizards tail-assisted self-righting abilities, with &lt;a href="http://me.berkeley.edu/~evancs/index.html"&gt;Evan Chang Siu&lt;/a&gt;, I got a chance to learn how to use &lt;a href="http://www.cadsoftusa.com/"&gt;EAGLE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In MSC lab, there is a board milling machine that mills out PCBs from copper plates. This allowed me to design circuit boards and then print them in the machine to receive operable circuit boards without the expensive and long turnover time from traditional PCB printers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;At first, I designed a breakout board for a simple SMD inverter (74LVC2G04). It was simple and all of the traces are on one side as well. This board simply alternates turning on the LEDs, depending on what signals are fed into the chip.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Drawing inspiration from &lt;a href="http://www.sparkfun.com/tutorials/138"&gt;Sparkfun&#x2019;s pogo beds&lt;/a&gt;, I then laid out a test probe board suitable for the Finch Chip, which was a wireless IMU with a tiny footprint developed by another graduate student in CiBER. Since the Finch Chip sacrificed headers for a small footprint, this test probe board breaks out all of the pins for repeatable and easy programming. As seen below, the Finch Chip would sit in the middle and the headers in the periphery would allow for programming and probing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Finally, I began work on the second iteration of Tailbot&#x2019;s control board. In order to free up several pins on the Arduino, I added an inverter to reduce the logic lines required to control the motor. In addition, I replaced the slow XBee and installed a Nordic transceiver (nRF24L01+) for the control board&#x2019;s wireless communications. The board schematic shown below features the inverter, which is placed on the bottom layer beneath the words &#x201C;Tailbot v2&#x201D; while the Nordic transceiver was placed towards the lower left of the board.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Once it is printed and populated, it would look like this. Ain&#x2019;t she a beauty?</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object031.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2012/3/1_First_PCB_layout%21.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network based Wireless Rehabilitation</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2011/6/1_Network_based_Wireless_Rehabilitation.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6cc4a305-a975-43a8-abb6-356f8a2d74d1</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 1 Jun 2011 23:28:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>As part of my research in the &lt;a href="http://msc.berkeley.edu/index.html"&gt;MSC lab&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="http://jbbae.info/index.html"&gt;Joonbum Bae&lt;/a&gt;, I worked on setting up the hardware and software for a proposed wireless sensor network for gait rehabilitation. The idea was that in classical gait rehabilitation therapy, there are no concrete numbers on which to base a diagnosis. Much of therapy done for a patient afflicted with a gait disorder is based on a therapist&#x2019;s physical observation. More often than not, the level of care is proportional to the therapist&#x2019;s experience.&lt;br/&gt;For patients with a gait disorder, it is often very difficult to physically transport themselves to receive therapy as well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As a result, we created a system where a patient will wear a series of intelligently placed sensor nodes (pictured below) that will record Euler angles and transfer it wirelessly to a local computer, which will then transfer it via Internet to the therapist&#x2019;s computer. The pre-populated circuit board is shown above.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;With Kevin Haninger, I worked on developing the software required to calculate the Euler angles in Arduino using &lt;a href="http://www.varesano.net/projects/hardware/FreeIMU"&gt;Varesano&#x2019;s FreeIMU library&lt;/a&gt; and packet loss compensation and visualization in LabVIEW. Each sensor node on the patient calculates Euler angles in the onboard Arduino. When prompted by the local computer, the Arduino will respond and return a set of measurements to the local computer, where LabVIEW will parse it and process the data into useful information. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This video, taken towards the end of summer, highlighted our first success with LabVIEW&#x2019;s tricky visualization VIs.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This video showcases our entire human model visualized in LabVIEW. Joonbum is shown here imitating faulty gait on the treadmill and assessing how well the wireless sensor network can capture that motion and translate it on the big screen.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We have since published our work into a conference paper at the &lt;a href="http://www.aim2012.org/"&gt;2012 IEEE/ASME International Conference on Advanced Intelligent Mechatronics&lt;/a&gt; and can be found &lt;a href="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/stamp/stamp.jsp?arnumber=06265884"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object001.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2011/6/1_Network_based_Wireless_Rehabilitation.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egg Mobile</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2011/5/7_Egg_Mobile.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">65a93696-4abb-488a-ba26-9aee5c3cbb31</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 7 May 2011 23:26:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href="http://pts.berkeley.edu/"&gt;Pi Tau Sigma&lt;/a&gt; is the National Mechanical Engineering Honor Society at UC Berkeley. One of the requirements to become a member was to participate in a pledge project, a group project completed by a group of pledges during their pledge semester.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In my pledge semester, the task was to design a vehicle to transport an egg safely to a target area about 25 feet away in a straight line. However, the tricky part was that the vehicle must be self-powered as well as able to clear a street curb that&#x2019;s along the way. The pledge group with the best score, determined by the time it took to complete the objective, if at all, would earn a set of free MATLAB shirts.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Melissa Wah, Robert Luan, Chris Gotianun, Ben Yee, and I brought our heads together and decided to design a two-stage vehicle that would approach the curb via a mousetrap. Once the vehicle hits the curb, a trigger would activate and start the launch of the mouse trap-powered 2nd stage vehicle. Our initial concept sketch looked something like this:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The car to the left is the first stage vehicle and would collide with the curb. The car on the right is the second stage and would carry the egg to the target area. Together, our vehicle looked like this:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;However, after we prototyped a mousetrap car, we quickly realized that it wasn&#x2019;t going to work. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Because of that test, we ended up converting to DC motors to power our vehicles. On Initiation, we pitted our vehicle against 4 other pledge groups. Although we were doing well in the beginning, an evil gust blew our second stage vehicle off course and away from the target zone :(&lt;br/&gt;We ended up with second place instead. Regardless, the pledge project was really fun and definitely a memorable milestone in my college career.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object024.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2011/5/7_Egg_Mobile.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Target Shooting</title>
      <link>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2010/11/15_Target_Shooting.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">962f5b9c-a77e-4f25-835d-76018af46417</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 17:20:47 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>E28 was an introduction course to basic engineering graphics design. In short, it&#x2019;s a class where I learned how to use CAD (Computer Aided Design) software, like AutoCAD and Solidworks.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It culminates in a month-long group project that varies with the semester. In Fall 2010, the project goal was to &#x201C;design a mechanism so a ball (rubber ball) rolled or dropped into the device is automatically fired towards a target some distance away from the mechanism&#x201D;. The target ended up being a soda can and extra credit was going to be awarded to the group with the best performance.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I worked with Elina Lin, Chris Gebhart, Derek Remsburg, and Moonsoo Choi on this project and after some deliberation, we decided on a catapult, a design many other groups tried as well. Since it was to be fully automated after a ball is rolled in, we designed a trigger that locks due to friction.&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&lt;br/&gt;The trigger mechanism itself is tensioned with a rubber band that would keep it reclined, as shown above. The trigger keeps the arm in a loading configuration, as seen below. Once the ball rolls into the arm&#x2019;s cup, the dowel in the trigger would separate from the trigger and would be allowed to launch forward.&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&lt;br/&gt;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;This was, easily, one of the most punctual group project because we actually had time to test our project a week before the due date. Below are some action shots of us demolishing defenseless soda cans!&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&lt;br/&gt;On Presentation Day, we demonstrated our catapult&#x2019;s ability to knock over the soda can numerous times. You can see our final timed run in the Youtube video below. The final count was 15 cans, about 10 cans more compared to the next best-performing group. As a result, we ended up in 2nd place out of the entire class.&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&#x2028;&#x2028;&#x2028;All pictures used here belongs to Derek Remsburg and I give all credit to him.&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/object025.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects/Entries/2010/11/15_Target_Shooting.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <iweb:dateFormat>MMMM d, y</iweb:dateFormat>
    <iweb:baseURL>file://localhost/Users/dwai/Desktop/mysite/mysite/Projects</iweb:baseURL>
    <iweb:maximumSummaryItems>15</iweb:maximumSummaryItems>
  </channel>
</rss>
